vuukle.com 2019-03-03

# Vuukle Privacy Policy | Vuukle Docs

Who we are? What we do?

Vuukle is an audience engagement platform that provides engagement solutions to publishers to help increase engagement. We provide solutions like: 

  1. A power bar that helps count the number of shares and likes an article receives when user clicks on them. It is displayed at the top of the page to capture engagement.
  2. We provide a sentiment solution, popularly known as WHAT IS YOUR REACTION? that can be easily placed anywhere on the page to help users express their sentiment towards the article they just read. It helps the publisher understand how many people felt happy, sad or angry for that article.
  3. We also provide commenting solutions that is placed at the bottom of the article to build community engagement where users are allowed to express their opinion relating to the article by maintaining decent conversations.

What data we collect

**There are two cases here:**

  1. When a user opens a page powered by Vuukle technologies even without creating a Vuukle account. We collect the following data: 
    1. Device (mobile, desktop or tablet)
    2. OS (windows, mac, android etc)
    3. Browser (chrome, safari etc)
    4. IP Address, city and country
    5. Unique IDs such as a cookie ID on your browser
    6. the referring URL and the web search you used to locate and navigate to a Publisher Site
  2. By engaging in the comment section to express his/her view for which a user has to login. We collect the following data: 
    1. Device (mobile, desktop or tablet)
    2. OS (windows, mac, android etc)
    3. Browser (chrome, safari etc)
    4. IP Address, city and country
    5. Unique IDs such as a cookie ID on your browser
    6. Name
    7. Email

Purpose of collecting the above data

We use the information we collect from Vuukle powered site visitors to create a secure and personalized service.

  1. To count the number of users.
  2. To identify any form of bot traffic or spam/abuse to protect our systems and to keep the platform civil.
  3. Create a commenting profile of the user so that he/she can manage and see a history of their comments at one place.
  4. We use analytics services which set and collect cookie IDs for purposes of understanding Vuukle Site Visitors' loyalty to the Site. We use the IP addresses to assist in login and other uses related to use of the Service. Vuukle Site Visitors sessions on Our Site are also tracked for systems administration purposes and to track user trends.
  5. Verify genuine user profiles to provide genuine community.
  6. Reduce the barrier of logging in again and again for the user to write a comment on Vuukle on all websites across the globe who use Vuukle.
  7. To display comment threads for Vuukle powered site visitors to read and engage with you on your comments.
  8. To notify users by email when his comment is published or replied by other users.

Whom we share your data with

Vuukle automatically stores your data when data subject visits or comments or interacts on publisher sites powered by Vuukle technologies. In this case the data is shared with that publisher only who becomes responsible to maintain its own privacy policy as per GDPR EU law which came into effect on 25th May 2018.

For example: Vuukle will share data with website XYZ of only those users who commented on website XYZ. If 5000 websites across the globe use Vuukle platform we will not share your data to all those 5000 sites. Only and only to those publishers where the respective user has engaged.

Vuukle does not share any kind of user data with any ad networks. We do not sell your data to any one. We only collect just the minimum data required in order to serve you better.

For how long we store your data

The user data stored by Vuukle exists with Vuukle for as long as the user has their profiles maintained with us. The data will be deleted whenever a user decides to delete his/her profile over which user has complete control.

How you can delete your data

You may delete your Vuukle account by following the instructions found at this link: [Delete my Vuukle account.](https://docs.vuukle.com/how-to-delete-your-account/)

In case you are unable to delete your data we are here to help you for any support, requests can be sent to [support@vuukle.com](mailto:support@vuukle.com) After a user requests to delete his/her profile data, the data will be deleted from Vuukle servers with in 30 days or a maximum of 75 days if there are many such requests. 

Right to be forgotten

To delete any data stored with the respective publishers powered by Vuukle, Vuukle will forward your query to the publisher for deletion and we expect everyone to follow the rules and guidelines. Vuukle will not be liable whether the data has been deleted or not by the publisher on their end as GDPR EU law equally applies to the publisher.

If the user decides to come back again they will have to create a fresh profile like a new user.

Children's policy

Services provided by Vuukle are not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Since Vuukle does not collect any data on age we do not know if a person who has created an account is under the age of 13 or not. In case we learn or is notified that a certain profile is under the age of 13, Vuukle will delete it. If parents have any information regarding the same they can contact us for deletion.

Third party or publicly available sources

When a user logs in into our system for commenting from various social networks like Facebook connect, google or twitter your account is automatically linked to Vuukle commenting services. In such cases we collect users personal data on only three parameters that is name of the user, email of the user and avatar of the user. The user can later customise their avatar by managing their profile page on Vuukle. Also, the deletion policy will apply as narrated above.

Targeted advertising and AD partners

We work with many third party ad partners to serve ads which are displayed around the Vuukle widgets on publisher sites to the user. Vuukle does not share any user information with these partners, however, in the course of serving or displaying ads through Vuukle, these partners may place a cookie on your browser. We expect all third party partners to follow all relevant privacy laws and regulations(including GDPR EU law) when serving ads through Vuukle, who collect users information like, [cookie IDs, device IDs (including mobile), hashed email addresses, IP address, ISP and browser information, demographic or interest data, content viewed and actions taken on the Service or Partner Sites, including information about the websites you’ve viewed and advertisements you’ve interacted within order to provide you with more relevant advertising targeted to your preferences and interests derived from your interaction with the Service, Partner Sites or other third party websites.

Vuukle has no control over these ads partners as they are independent of Vuukles’ control. Vuukle owns no responsibility for any data of the data subject they store.

To learn more about this type of targeted advertising (also called interest-based advertising), analytics services and your choices, including how to opt-out of some third party ads, advertising networks and ad servers, please visit the [DAA Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/), [NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), and [Google's information page.](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

Opting out of newsletters

You may opt-out of Newsletters and promotional emails from us at any time by using the opt-out mechanism contained in such emails (also referred to as "unsubscribe"). Please note, unsubscribing from Vuukle emails will unsubscribe you from Vuukle notification emails and Vuukle digest emails. You will still receive transactional emails necessary for the Vuukle service to function, these include, but may not be limited to, emails confirming you created a new account, emails helping you reset your password etc. 

Disclosures of your personal data

In any case we acquire other businesses or may choose to sell, transfer or merge our parts of business with others Vuukle may have to share users personal data that it collects with these other parties.

In addition to the above, we may access, preserve, and disclose your personal data, including your Identity, Contact, or Technical data, if we believe doing so is required or appropriate to comply with law enforcement requests and legal process, such as a court order, government request, or subpoena, or to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also access, preserve, and disclose such personal data if we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect yours', ours' or others' rights, property, or safety, or to investigate fraud.

Declining Cookies

If you do not want to accept our cookies, you can adjust your browser settings to decline cookies. You should note, however, that certain areas of the Site may not operate properly if you decide not to accept cookies.

Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so. Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

Security

All commercially reasonable safety procedures are taken by Vuukle for user information collected through Vuukle services and we make sure that we are preserving the privacy and security of the your data.

You have complete control over your profile but before granting you access to your profile we request a unique password to verify your identity. Once you are granted the access from thereon you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Vuukle. Your privacy settings may also be altered by accessing the Service through a third party such as social networks. Vuukle is not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party.

California privacy rights

California law gives residents of California the right under certain circumstances to request information from us regarding the manner in which we share certain categories of personal data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Because our Privacy Policy gives you a choice of opting out of having your contact information disclosed to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, we may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your preferences. To request such information, please contact us at [privacy@vuukle.com](mailto:privacy@vuukle.com)

General

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@Vuukle.com](mailto:privacy@vuukle.com), or contact us by mail at _Unit No. 2980,DMCC Business Centre, Level No. 1, Dubai,UAE_

Changes to Privacy Policy. Vuukle may, in its sole discretion, modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time, and so you should review this page periodically. When we change the policy, we will update the ‘last modified’ date at the bottom of this page. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes.

This Privacy Policy was last modified on May, 2018.
